Guide to the Jack Censer collection, 1953-2011
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
Jack Censer collection
1953-2011
1970s-2011
C0241
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
18 linear feet (45 boxes)
This collection documents Censer’s work as a historian and as a professor, History and Art History Department Chair, and Dean of the College of Humanities and Social Sciences at George Mason University. The research files include his work on French history as well as his research on the D.C. Sniper and the media in 2002.
Censer, Jack Richard
Access Restrictions
A small amount of material is embargoed due to FERPA, Personally Identifiable Information, or in the interest of privacy. Folders that are restricted are marked in the contents list.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Jack Censer in 2013 and 2016.
Biographical Information
A historian of France (particlulary the 18th century and the French Revolution), Jack Censer is an emeritus professor of history and former chair of the History and Art History department and Dean of the College of Humanities and Social Sciences at George Mason University. Censer received his BA from Duke University and his MA and PhD from Johns Hopkins University. He taught at the College of Charleston in South Carolina before coming to George Mason University in 1977, where he taught a wide range of classes, from undergraduate courses in Western Civilization to graduate seminars on the French Revolution. His wife, Jane Turner Censer, is also a professor in the George Mason University History and Art History department.
Jack Censer has done significant work studying the French 18th century press, including a great deal of archival research both in France and the United States, and he has written numerous books and articles. His interest in the press and the media also led him to write a study of the media response to the 2002 D.C. Sniper shootings, 'On the Trail of the DC Sniper: Fear and the Media.' Censer retired from Mason in 2015 (History and Art History Department, George Mason University, 'Jack R. Censer').
Bibliography
Related Material
The Special Collections Research Center also holds the papers of other George Mason University professors as well as collections on the French Revolution and other periods of French history.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following 6 series, arranged by the archivist based on their organization by Jack Censer:
Series 1: Offprints, 1953-2010 (Boxes 1-17)
Series 2: D.C. Sniper research, 2002-2010 (Boxes 17-24)
Series 3: Teaching, circa 1960s-2003 (Boxes 24-27)
Series 4: Research, 1968-2006 (Boxes 27-42)
Series 5: Administrative papers, 1972-2011 (Boxes 42-44)
Series 6: Audiovisual materials, 2001-circa 2010s (Box 45)
Scope and Content
This collection contains material from throughout Jack Censer's career as a researcher, historian of the French Revolution, university professor, and administrator.
Series 1: Offprints contains articles collected by Censer throughout his career that date from 1953-2010. Most of the articles are from scholarly publications and deal with French history, particularly French 18th century history, although other places and times are represented. Some of the articles have notes to Censer and are signed by the author. The series also contains a number of reviews published in journals by Censer. There is a mixture of photocopies and original printings.
Series 2: D.C. Sniper research contains notes, printouts of television transcripts and print coverage, and other research material dating from 2002-2010, collected in the course of Censer's work on his book 'On the Trail of the D.C. Sniper: Fear and the Media' between 2002-2010.
Series 3: Teaching consists largely of syllabi, exam questions, and paper prompts for Jack Censer's graduate and undergraduate classes dating from the 1960s-2003, though mostly from his time as a professor in the history department at George Mason University.
Series 4: Research (1968-2006) contains material used in Censer's research on the press in 18th century France, as well as various aspects of the French Revolutionary era (mostly photocopies). It also contains multiple versions of some of Censer's scholarly output and related material, including articles, book chapters, essays from his time as a student, publishing logistical materials, reviews, and correspondence. Also included are materials from Censer's participation in professional organizations such as the American Historical Association.
Series 5: Administrative papers contains material from 1972-2011 that documents Censer's work as Chair of the Art and Art History department at George Mason University. Also included are materials for work he did beyond the university for the Educational Testing Service and Bryant Adult Center, as well as correspondence and graduation programs from other institutions.
Series 6: Audiovisual materials dates from 2001 to circa 2010s and largely contains CDs of D.C. Sniper-related research materials and copies of Microsoft Word, Eudora, and Outbox files. There is also an interview on two audiocassettes.
Index Terms
Person
Censer, Jack Richard
Corporate Names:
George Mason University.
Subjects:
Criminal snipers--Washington Metropolitan Area.
Geographical Names:
France--History--Revolution, 1789-1799.
Contents List
- Series 1: Offprints, 1953-2010 (Boxes 1-17)
  This series contains articles collected by Censer throughout his career that date from 1953-2010. Most of the articles are from scholarly publications and deal with French history, particularly French 18th century history, although other places and times are represented. Some of the articles have notes to Censer and are signed by the author. The series also contains a number of reviews published in journals by Censer. There is a mixture of photocopies and original printings.
  - Ackerman, Evelyn, review by Jack Censer, circa 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ackerman, Evelyn, "The Social and Economic Development of Bonneres-sur-Seine in the Nineteenth Century,", circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albright, Madeleine, "Poland: The Role of the Press in Political Change,", 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Allen, James Smith, "A Distant Echo: Reading Jules Michelet's 'L'Amour' and La Femme in 1859-1860,", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allen, James review by Jack Censer and related material, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Anderson, Alan D., Patricia Bryan, et al, "An Experiment in Combat Simulation: The Battle of Cambrai, 1917,", 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Andress, David review by Jack Censer (labelled Magerison), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Andrews, Stuart and Eagles, Robin review by Jack Censer, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Applewhite, Harriet, "Political Legitimacy in Revolutionary France,", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Armstrong, Elizabeth review by Jack Censer and related material, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Aron, Robert, "DeGaulle's Strategy,", 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Articles and offprints, 1997-2010 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ascoli, Peter articles and letters, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Aydelotte, William, "Quantification in History" and notes, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Azam, Denise Aime, "Le Ministere des Affaires etrangeres et la presse a la fin de l'Ancienne Regime," 1938 (photocopy), circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Baker, Keith articles, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Baker project, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bakhash, Shaul, articles, 1992, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Beck, Thomas, "The French Revolution and the Nobility: A Reconsideration,", 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Barker, articles, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bell, David, articles, 1998-2001 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bell, David, reviews by Jack Censer, other reviews, 1990s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Benhamou, Paul articles, 1988, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bergson, Henri, "An Introduction to Metaphysics,", circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Berier, Oliver review by Jack Censer and related material, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Berkner, Lutz, "The Stem Family and the Development of the Peasant Household,", 1972 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Berlanstein, Lenard articles, 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Beyer, Barry, "Using Writing to Learn in History,", 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Blakemore, Steven and Michael Sonenscher review by Jack Censer, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Blaufarb, Rafe articles, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Birn, Raymond articles, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Black, Jeremy review by Jack Censer, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Black, Jeremy articles, 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bodecker, Hans Erich articles, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bonjean, Wirt, Mortlock articles, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bontoux, Francoise, "Les Nouvelles Ecclesiastiques," 1955 (photocopy), undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bordes, Philippe, "Les musees et l'histoire,", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bosher, J.F. articles, 1972, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bosher, J.F. review by Jack Censer, late 1980s (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bossenga, Gail review by Jack Censer and related material, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Botein, Stephen, Clark, Charles, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bots, Hans and Van Dijk, Suzanna reviews by Jack Censer and letter, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Boxer, Marilyn, "Foyer or Factory,", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Branca, Patricia - Chapter from "Silent Sisterhood,", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Brenner, "The Community Cabaret,", circa 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Brooks, Gary H., "Hattie and Huey: A reexamination of the Arkansas Senatorial Primary of 1932,", 1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Bryant, Lawrence, "Royal Ceremony and the Revolutionary Strategies of the Third Estate,", undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Burkhard, Fred Bud articles, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Calhoun, Craig articles, 1983, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cameron, Rondo articles, 1958, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Cameron, Iain review by Jack Censer, circa 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Chartier, Roger article and review, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Chartier, Roger review by Jack Censer, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Chartier, Roger review by Jack Censer, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cartier, Roger and Henri-Jean Martin, "Histoire de l'edition francaise" review by Jack Censer, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Chisick, Harvey articles, 1975-2001 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Chronicle of Higher Education article, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Clark, Charles, "A 'Free Press' and the Evolution of Newspaper Ethics in Eighteenth Century America,", 1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Collins, James B., "The Economic Role of Women in Seventeenth-Century France,", circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Clifford, Dale and Jane Decker articles, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Cobban, A., "The 'Middle Class' in France, 1815-48,", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Cohn, Jan, "The Business Ethic for Boys,", 1987 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Colton, Joel article, photocopy of 1966 outline, 1960s, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Colwill, Elizabeth, "Pass like a woman, act like a man,", 1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Corbin, Alain review by Jack Censer, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Couperus, Mariane, "Le Glaneur Historique,", 1971 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Creel, Kat, "Mistress and Maid,", 1980 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Crew, David articles, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Crout, Robert articles, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Crook, Malcolm review by Jack Censer, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - D'Amico, John articles, 1980-1991 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Darnton, Robert reviews by Jack Censer, 1980s-1996 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Darnton, Robert reviews, 1978-circa 1990s (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Darnton, Eisenstein, Febvre G Martin, "Publishing in Early Modern Europe,", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Darnton, Robert and Daniel Roche review by Jack Censer, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Davis, Clarence articles, 1979, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Davis, Natalie, "The Sacred and the Body Social in Sixteenth-Century Lyon,", circa 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Davis, Natalie, "Society and Culture in Early Modern France" review by Jack Censer, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Deshmukh, Marion articles, 1979-1998 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dewald, Jonathan, "A Gentry Community in Early Modern France,", circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Deane, Seamus review by Jack Censer, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Dechair, Somerset ed. "Napoleon on Napoleon" review by Jack Censer, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Delemeau, Jean, "Catholicism between Luther and Voltaire,", undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Dempsey, John, "Carter Reorganization,", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Doyle, William articles, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Diefendorf, Barbara, "Widowhood and Remarriage in Sixteenth-Century Paris,", 1982 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Diner, Steven articles, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Dooley, Brendan articles, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Drescher, Seymour articles, 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Dufraisse, Roger, "Napoleon" (1 of 2), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Dufraisse, Roger, "Napoleon" (2 of 2), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Duplessis and Howell, "Reconsidering the Early Modern Urban Economy,", 1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Drago, Edmund, "Military and Black Women in Reconstruction Georgia,", circa 1970s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Echeverria, Durand articles, 1953, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Edelstein, Melvin articles, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Eisenstein, Elizabeth articles, 1984-1998 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Ellis, Geoffrey review by Jack Censer, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Ellis, Harold chapters, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Eloge de Feu M. Roux, photocopy, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Fairchilds, Cissie articles, circa 1970s, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Feyel, Gilles articles, 1980s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Feyel, Gilles review by Jack Censer, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Ffoliott, Sheila articles and outline, 1982-1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Field, Frank review by Jack Censer, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Fink, Caroline, "Marc Bloch,", 1988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Fontana, Biancamaria review by Jack Censer, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Forster and Ranum review by Jack Censer, circa 1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Forster, Robert articles (1 of 2), 1970s (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Forster, Robert articles (2 of 2), 1970s (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Forster, Robert, "The 'world' between seigneur and peasant,", 1976 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - French Revolution reviews, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Friguglietti, James articles, 1974, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Furet, Francois, "The French Revolution Revisited,", 1980 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Galambos, Louis articles, 1968, 1971, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Gaurioch, David review by Jack Censer, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Geertz, Hildred article, Natalie Davis article, 1974, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Gelbart, Nina articles, circa 1980s (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - George Mason affiliated authors' papers, 2000s-2010s (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Golden, Richard, "The Mentality of Opposition,", 1978 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Goldman, Peter articles, undated, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Goodman, Dena articles, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Graff, Harvey, "Reflections on the History of Literacy,", 1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Grafton, Anthony, "The Importance of Being Printed,", 1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Graham, Hugh Davis, "The Paradox of Eleanor Roosevelt,", 1987 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Graham, Ruth, "The Challenge of Secularization to the Sacraments under the First French Republic,", circa 1970s (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Greenberg, Janelle, "The Legal Status of the English Woman in Early Eighteenth-Century Common Law and Equity,", 1975 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Greenlaw, Ralph, "A Proposal Looking to the Establishment of a Computerized (Machine-Readable) Bibliography of French Revolutionary Pamphlets,", circa 1970s (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Gruder, Vivian articles, 1978-1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Gunn, J.A.W., "Beyond Liberty and Property,", 1983 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Grieder, Josephine, conclusion to "Anglomania in France, 1740-1789,", 1985 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Grendler, Paul, "The Impact of Printing," XX 851 D2 c.1, circa 1980s (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Haakonssen, Knud, "Natural Jurisprudence in the Scottish Enlightenment,", 1989 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Habermas, Jurgen, "Further Reflections on the Public Sphere,", circa 1989-early 1990s (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Hagy, James William articles, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Halevi, Ran articles, 1985-2004 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Hanson, Paul review by Jack Censer, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Harris, Michael, "The Structure, Ownership, and Control of the Press, 1620-1780,", undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Harris, William, "Work and the Family in Black Atlanta, 1880,", undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Harsanyi, Donia and Quinney, Anne, "Le Gout de la Revolte,", 2008 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Harsin, Jill letter to Jack Censer from Coburn re:article, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Harsin, Jill review by Jack Censer, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Harris journal article, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Henriques, Peter articles, 1989, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Herman, Arthur articles, 1980s-1990s (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Hesse, Carla, "Economic Upheavals in Publishing,", 1987 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Hesse, Carla review by Jack Censer, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Higonnet, Patrice article and review by Censer, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Higonnet, Patrice, "Le Sens de la Terreur dans la Revolution Francaise,", 1986 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - "Histoire D'Edition Francaise,", 1985 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Hofmeister, "Prussian Revindications and Enlightened 'Beamtentum' (Systems of Bureaucracy, Perhaps) in Ansbach-Bayreuth,", circa 1970s-1980s (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Holt, Mack articles, 1989-1999 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Hood, Chalmers, "The French Navy and Parliament between the Wars,", 1984 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Hoopes, James articles, 1977-1983 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Hopkins, George, "The Politics of Food,", 1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Howe, Pat, "The Pre-Revolutionary Press,", circa 1970s-1980s (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Howells, Michael articles and reviews, 1984-1986 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Hobohm, Hans-Christophe articles and print-out, 1980s (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Hudson, David, "The Last Years of the Nouvelles Ecclesiastiques,", circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Hufton, Olwen, "Women and the Family Economy in Eighteenth Century France,", 1974 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Hunt, Lynn articles, 1983-1998 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Hutt, Maurice, article and review by Censer, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Hutton, Patrick, "The History of Mentalities,", 1984 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Idzerda, "When and why Lafayette Became a Revolutionary,", circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Isaac, Rhys, "Learning and Authority,", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Isherwood, Robert, "Entertainment in the Parisian Fairs in the Eighteenth Century,", 1981 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Jacob, Margaret, "The Enlightenment Redefined,", 1991 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Jensen, Ronald, "Eugene Schuyler and the Balkan Crisis,", circa 1970s (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Johnson, Hubert review by Jack Censer, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Jones, Colin, "The Great Chain of Buying,", 1996 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Jordan, David review by Jack Censer, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Joughin, "The Uses of Power in the Blanzy Basin from the Beginnings to World War I,", undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Kaiser, Thomas articles, 1981-1998 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Kaplan, Steven, "The Luxury Guilds in Paris in the Eighteenth Century,", 1982 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Kaplan, Steven review by Jack Censer, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Kates, Gary articles, 1978-1989 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Kearney, Hugh, "The Problem of Perspective in the History of Colonial America,", 1979 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Kelly, George, "Alphonse de la Martine,", 1987 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Kelly, T. Mills, "New Ideas in Teaching,", 2001 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Kemnitz, Thomas, "The Cartoon as a Historical Source,", 1973 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Kennedy, Emmet articles, circa 1970s, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Kennedy, Michael, "The Development of a Political Radical, Jean-Louis Carra, 1742-1787,", circa 1970s (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Kenyon, J.P., "Rights: Where Did the Concept of Rights Come From?,", mid-1980s (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Kettering, Sharon articles, 1981-1986 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Kieswetter, James, "The Imperial Restoration,", circa 1975 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Kirkland, John review of Allan Megill's "The Prophets of Extremity,", 1987 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Klaits, Joseph articles, circa 1970s, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Klancher, Jon, "The Making of English Reading Audience,", 1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Klein, Daniel, Murray Rothbard articles, 1974, circa late 1970s (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Kramer, Lloyd review by Jack Censer, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Krech, Stephen articles, 1980-1988 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Labrosse, Claude articles, 1976-1990 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Labrosse, Claude review by Jack Censer, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Landes, David, "French Entrepreneurship and Industrial Growth in the Nineteenth Century," circa 1940s, photocopy, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Landsberg, Alison, "America, the Holocaust, and the Mass Culture of Memory,", 1997 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Lasch, Christopher, "The Family and History,", 1975 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Laux, James review by Jack Censer, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - LaVolpa, Anthony articles, 1991, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Lebrun, Francois, "Une Source de l'Histoire Sociale,", undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - LeGoff, T.J.A. articles, 1995-1997 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Leith, James, "Media and Revolution,", 1968 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Levy, Darlene articles, 1978-1981 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Liggio, Leonard articles, 1977-1978, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Livesy, James review by Jack Censer, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Loft, Lenore articles, circa 1980s, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Lubove, Roy, "Frederic C. Howe and the Quest for Community in America,", 1977 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Lucas, Colin, "The Crowd and Politics between Ancien Regime and Revolution in France,", 1988 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Ludtke, Alf, "The State and Social Domination in Eighteenth and Nineteenth Century Prussia,", 1981 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Lynn, John, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Lyons, Martyn review by Jack Censer, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Lyons, Martyn review by Jack Censer and letter from Thomas Schaeper, 1978, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Malino, Frances, Zalkind Hourwitz, Juif Polonais,", 1981 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Mallet du Pan, Jacques, "Considerations on the Nature of the French Revolution and on the Causes with Prolong its Duration," 1793, copy, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Mallon, Thomas, "Quiet Goes the Don,", 1989 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Margerison, Kenneth, "Political Pamphlets, the Society of Thirty, and the Failure to Create a Discourse of National Reform During the French Revolution, 1788-1789,", 1993 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Marion, Michael, "Dix Ans Des Affiches, Annonces, et Avis Divers," 1980, photocopy, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Marker, Gary review by Jack Censer, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Martin, Benjamin review by Jack Censer, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Maza, Sarah articles, 1987-1996 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - McBride, Theresa, "Ni Bourgeoises, Ni Proletaires: Women Sales Clerks, 1870-1920,", 1977 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - McCandless, Peter articles, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - McCusker, John, "The Rise of the Business Press in Early Modern Europe,", 1985 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - McKee, Kenneth, "The Role of the Priest on the Parisian Stage During the French Revolution" 1939, photocopy, circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - McKenzie, Lionel, "Rousseau's Debate with Machiavelli in 'The Social Contract' ,", 1982 (Box 10, Folder 20)